Pegasus Buchanan Papers
Pegasus Buchanan Papers
1948-1964
Buchanan, Pegasus, 1918-2006.
1 linear ft.
Manuscripts, newspaper and magazine clippings, published material, complete run (14 issues) of L.A. Magazine, of which Buchanan was poetry editor.
2764891
Biographical History
Pegasus Buchanan (1918-2006) was an American poet. Born in Lansing, Michigan she graduated from Michigan State University and in 1950 moved to Pomona, California with her husband Barney Barnum, where she became involved with the literary and artistic life of the community. She was the poetry editor of the Southern California publication L.A. Magazine for a number of years and received numerous awards, including the Pomona Valley Award for the promotion of children's literature, the Pomona Valley Library Award, and the College Arts Award. The Pomona Valley Writers Club established the annual Pegasus Award in her name, which honors children for their poetry.
Her published collections include Chestnut Street, Kingsley Alley and Wilderness Trail, and her poems appeared in many national magazines, including The Saturday Evening Post, Good Housekeeping, The Ladies' Home Journal, McCall's, The Saturday Review, and The New York Times.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Pegasus Buchanan Papers consists of manuscripts and published material.
Manuscripts include an unpublished book of children's verses entitled Talamo Tales, a galley proof of Kingsley Alley, and the original working copies of Chestnut Street and Kingsley Alley.
Published material includes scrapbooks of newspaper and periodical clippings by Buchanan, and about her and her work. Also included is a complete run (14 issues) of L.A. Magazine and all of the poetry Buchanan collected during her term as poetry editor for that publication. A copy of one of her books, Wilderness Trail, is also included.
Arrangement of the Collection
Other than the division into manuscript and published material, material is in no particular order.
Subject and Genre Headings
Literature -- American Poetry; Women Authors; Buchanan, Pegasus, 1918-2006.; L.A. magazine.; Women poets -- United States.; Pomona (Calif.) -- Intellectual life.; Books.; Clippings (information artifacts); Manuscripts for publication.; Galley proofs.; Scrapbooks.; Editors.; Poets.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Peggy Buchanan, 1965.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - Curtis Publishing Company / Saturday Evening Post, 1952; regarding her poem "Culprit" (Box 1)
    Acquired separately from the rest of the collection, 2016.
- Manuscripts
  - Chestnut Street, working copy (Box 1)
  - Kingsley Alley, 1963; galleys (Box 1)
  - Kingsley Alley, working copy (Box 1)
  - Talamo Tales, 1948; typescript (Box 1)
- Published material
  - Book, Wilderness Trail, 1948 (Box 1)
  - Newspaper clippings about, 1956-1964; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - L.A. Magazine, 1958-1961; also includes some extra partial copies; 14 issues (Box 2)
  - Periodical clippings about, 1959-1961 (Box 2)